みなさん…手首に このバンドを
付けておいて下さい｡➡
Everyone,
please put this bracelet around your wrist.
これは まあ
お守りみたいなモノです｡➡
This is like a good luck charm.
試験が終わるまで
外さないで下さい｡
Please wear it at all times during the exam.
(新田)《何がお守りだよ…｡➡
A good luck charm?
これが何なのか
大体の検討はつく…》
I know what this really is.
《脈拍 体温 行動範囲や行動量➡
Heart rate, body temperature, range and frequency of movement...
とにかく 常に俺たちの
ストレス状態を見るもんだろう｡➡
They're constantly monitoring our stress levels.
こんなもんで 体調も精神状態も
見られてるわけか…｡➡
So this is all they need to track our physical and mental condition?
これじゃ便所に居たって…
気が抜けねぇな》
That means I can't even relax in the restroom...
≪下の名前で呼んでくれて
いいですよ≫
You can call me by my first name.
≪えっ!?…いいんですか？≫
Huh? C-Can I really?
はい｡
自分の名前 気に入ってるんです｡
Yes.
I happen to like my name.
えっ では…早速 ウホン｡
Th-Then I'll give it a try...
せ～りか…
うっ…うわ～っ!?
Seri—
ちょっと
そこ通してよ…お兄ちゃん｡
I need to get through, big brother.
《ムッ…また お兄ちゃん？》
He's still calling me that?
《まったく…お気楽な２人だ》
Seriously, they're way too relaxed.
Hey, Nitta...
おい 新田君！
フフッ｡俺のこと…下の名前で
呼んでくれても いいんだぜ？➡
You can call me by my first name.
まあ 別に気に入ってないけど｡
Though I don't particularly like it.
わかった｡
Okay.
次の課題で俺に勝てたら
呼んであげるよ…お兄ちゃん｡
If you beat me in the next task,
I'll use your first name, big brother.
この…｡
Space Brothers
Ah
This feels so good, different from usual
I have no idea what's going on
It feels so good
I never understand what's going on around me
Nothing makes sense to me
Full of questions
Feel so moon
I danced with you in a desert lit by the moon
I won't lose to the rabbit and fly high
I'll fly high
#13 3-D Ant
Could everyone please change into your jumpsuits?
(ｽﾋﾟｰｶｰ:鶴見)皆さん ジャージに
着替えて下さい｡
《気になるのは
このバンドだけじゃない｡➡
This bracelet isn't the only thing that's bugging me.
ルール…》
There's that rule...
⦅もうひとつ
ルールがあります｡➡
There is one additional rule I'd like to mention.
閉鎖ボックスに入ったら…
試験終了のｱﾅｳﾝｽが有るまで➡
Once you're inside the sealed box, you may not leave
絶対に外に出てはいけません｡
もし 誰か➡
until the end of the exam is announced.
If any individual steps outside,
ひとりでも外に出た場合は
その班 全員失格となります⦆
that person's entire team will be disqualified.
(新田)《｢全員失格｣って…➡
The entire team is disqualified?
That would be ridiculous after bringing us all out here.
そんな事ありえねぇだろ
募集しといて…｡➡
言われなくても途中で 外に
出るようなバカはいね～はず｡➡
No one would be stupid enough to go out during the exam.
なのに何で わざわざ
そんな忠告するんだ？》
So why did they feel it necessary to warn us?
(新田)《考え過ぎか…？》
Am I just being paranoid?
(新田)ハッ…ハッ…｡
1216 - 1160 -
計算ﾗﾝﾆﾝｸﾞ
(マシンの声)1216－1160＝？
(新田)５６！…ハッ…ハッ｡
56!
(音声)６４×１２＝？
64 x 12 -
７６８！
768!
(音声)終了デス｡
３８問 正解デス｡
Finish.
Thirty-eight questions answered correctly.
(古谷)《くっそ 速いな…》
スゲ～…｡
Damn, he's fast.
Wow...
あっ…ンッ ンッ…｡
(福田)ハッ…ハッ…｡
(音声)１２×４５＝？
12 x 45 -
ハッ…５４０！
540!
(音声)終了デス｡２３問 正解デス｡
Finish.
Twenty-three questions answered correctly.
(古谷)おっちゃんも やりよんな｡
おっちゃんやのに｡
Not too bad for an old-timer.
ハァ～…｡こりゃ
いい運動になる…アッハハ…｡
That was a good workout!
次は…お兄ちゃんの番だな｡
Big brother's up next.
Okay!
＜走りながら５分間で
何問 解けるかという➡
This is called Running Math, where you answer as many questions as possible in five minutes, all while running.
計算ランニング｡
これから 毎日やるらしい＞
It sounds like we'll be doing this every day.
ハッ…ハッ…｡
(音声)４５×８２＝？
45 x 82 -
Uh...
ええ～っと…3690！
3,690!
ハッ…ハッ…｡
(音声)８６×１５６＝？
86 x 156 -
Hmm...
13,316!
おお～い…｡フッ…フッ…｡
What?
＜正解すると｢ピンコン｣
間違うと｢ブッブー｣の➡
When you answer correctly, there's a ding-dong.
When you answer incorrectly, you get the buzzer.
効果音がなる｡どちらも うっすら
小バカにされてる感じの音だ＞
Both of these sound effects are pretty insulting.
ハッ…ハッ…｡
《負けねぇぞ～！新田に勝って
｢ムｯちゃん｣って呼ばせてやる｡➡
I'm not gonna lose!
I'll beat Nitta and make him call me Mu...
俺の唯一の特技
｢エアそろばん｣でな！》
By using my one specialty, the air abacus!
＜私は そろばんを目の前に
イメージすることができる｡➡
I have the ability to visualize an abacus.
そりゃあ もうリアルに！＞
It's incredibly realistic.
ハッ…ハッ…｡
ハァ～…ハァハァ…｡
ハァハァ…ハァ…ハァ…｡
ハァ…ハァ…チキショ～｡
Damn...
ヒハハッ｡やっぱり
エアそろばんなんて➡
Your air abacus was just a pose.
格好だけやったな｡
ボロボロやんけ～｡
That was pathetic.
You only got four questions right!
正解数４問って！
《ア～～ッ…！》
そろばん習ってない小学生でも
もうちょっと 正解すんで｡
I bet grade school kids who can't even use an abacus would've done better.
《クッ…｡普通に
計算した方が早かった｡➡
It would have been faster to crunch the numbers in my head!
そろばんのイメージを
リアルに再現し過ぎてしまった｡➡
My mental abacus was too realistic!
もう 走ってるから
動く動く…》
The beads kept sliding around because I was running!
⦅あれっ…あっ…⦆
ハァ～～…｡
げきちん
《俺の唯一の特技が…撃沈だ》
My only specialty was a complete failure...
残念だな お兄ちゃん｡
また明日…勝負してあげるよ｡
Too bad, big brother.
You can try again tomorrow.
《くそぅ…負けねぇぞ 新田！➡
Damn...
I refuse to lose, Nitta!
この２週間以内に絶対
｢ムッちゃん｣って呼ばせてやる》
I'll make you call me Mu before the two weeks end!
(ｽﾋﾟｰｶｰ:鶴見)さあ 次の課題です｡
パスボックスに➡
We'll now move on to the next task.
Laptops have been placed in the pass-through box.
ノートパソコンを
入れておきました｡➡
Please take them to the experiment module.
実験モジュールに運んで下さい｡
＜パソコンを使った
｢打ち込み練習｣なる➡
The laptops were for a two-hour typing test.
２時間のテスト｡
用紙に書かれた文字列を➡
We had to copy a wall of text from
ひたすら 画面に打ち込んでいく｡
こんなのを…＞
a handout.
あれ どこまでいったっけ？
…Ｆ…Ｂ…ＪＣ…｡
Huh? Where was I?
F, B, J, C...
ふぅ…｡私 やっと一行め｡
I finally finished the first line.
目の良い運動になるな｡
アッハハハ…｡
This is good exercise for the eyes.
＜集中力と持久力の…
まさに単純作業｡➡
This is very simple work that evaluates concentration and endurance.
だけど
このぐらいの課題なら…＞
But I've seen worse...
よしっ！
There.
(新田)《みんな ガキみて～に
感情を表に出し過ぎだ》
They're displaying their emotions like children.
こうふん
《こんなゲームに興奮したり…
焦ったり…いらついたり…➡
Showing excitement, worry, and irritation over a little game.
はっきりいって それじゃダメだ｡
どんな時でも冷静に判断し➡
And frankly, that's the wrong approach.
You must be able to remain calm and deliberate at all times.
行動できる人間｡そうでなければ
…火星なんて無理だ》
Or else you'll never make it to Mars.
(新田)《この班で選ばれる２人は
誰だか知らんが…➡
Out of this team, I have no idea who will make it,
ジャクサ
ＪＡＸＡ側が選ぶのは
そういう人材だろう｡➡
but I assume that's what JAXA is looking for.
誰が一番冷静かを
数値で見るために…➡
They want a quantitative measure of our ability to keep calm.
この黒いバンドがあるんだ》
That's what this black bracelet does.
(ｽﾋﾟｰｶｰ:鶴見)次の課題です｡➡
Moving to the next task.
まずは これを見て下さい｡
First, please watch this.
ごく最近 放送された
あるニュース番組です｡➡
This is from a recent news program.
からくち
辛口ｺﾒﾝﾄが売りの塩川ｷｬｽﾀｰの
次の発言を聞いて下さい｡
Pay attention to the commentary from the anchor, Shiokawa, who's known for being critical.
[VTR](塩川)
でもほら 宇宙開発って
物凄い予算を使ってますよね｡➡
However, space exploration requires a great deal of money.
それもみんな 私たちが
払っている税金なわけですよ｡➡
Our tax money supports these activities.
無人ロケット１回で２００億｡
人を打ち上げるとなったら➡
It costs 20 billion to launch an unmanned rocket.
Launching a manned rocket would cost 60 billion.
１回で６００億かかるって
話じゃないですか｡
[VTR](塩川)
その割に有人宇宙飛行での
科学的成果が見られないですよね｡
Meanwhile, we have yet to see any benefit to society.
地球上に解決すべき問題が
山積みなのに➡
There are many other problems that need to be solved,
そんなことに お金を使うのは
どうかと私は思うわけです｡
so I must question the funding being provided.
以上です｡➡
That concludes the clip.
彼女の発言は 今とても
力を持っています｡➡
Her words carry significant influence.
これを聞いた多くの視聴者は➡
Many viewers will see space exploration in a negative light.
宇宙開発を
軽視するようになるでしょう｡➡
正直 それでは困るのです｡
我々ＪＡＸＡとしても➡
Honestly, that could be problematic.
The people of JAXA are proud of the work that we do.
プライドを持って
仕事をしているわけですから➡
我々は この塩川ｷｬｽﾀｰに
抗議文を送ろうと考えています｡
We intend to send a letter of protest to Shiokawa.
ですが 彼女の発言も
決して間違いではないので➡
However,
she makes a number of good points, which only makes it more difficult for us.
難しいところです｡そこで
皆さんに これを課題として➡
So we would like you to discuss this matter within your teams.
話し合って頂きます｡
…もう おわかりですね｡
I'm sure you see where I'm going.
《きた…》
Here it is.
Please write a letter that will win her over.
彼女を納得させられるような
文章を作って下さい｡
宇宙開発に対して
批判的な塩川キャスター｡➡
Shiokawa is a journalist who strongly opposes space exploration.
彼女を納得させられるような
文章を作って下さい｡
Please write a letter that will win her over.
＜私は…
子供の頃 日々人と聞いた➡
That was when I recalled
something Hibito and I heard
Astronaut
Noguchi Soichi
Lecture
from Noguchi Soichi when we were kids.
宇宙飛行士 野口聡一さんの
話を思い出していた＞
すげぇ～｡すげぇ！
本物だぞ 日々人！
Wow!
Wow, Hibito! It's the real Noguchi!
ひびと
(日々人)うん！野口さんだ！
Yep, it's Noguchi!
(野口さん)ええ 今日はですね｡
え～ 僕は何で人間が➡
Today, I would like to discuss why humans should go into space.
宇宙に行くかということを
お話ししたいと思います｡➡
地上にも いろいろ問題が
あるよね｡環境問題だったり➡
There are many unresolved issues on Earth,
ええ…人種の問題だったり
それから経済の問題だったり➡
such as the environment or race problems,
as well as the economy.
So why should we explore space,
いろいろ問題があるけども
じゃあ 何で➡
when we haven't solved all of our problems on Earth?
宇宙にいかなきゃいけないのか｡
僕は そういう時に➡
There's this metaphor that I like to use.
ひとつの
たとえ話を いつもします｡➡
ええ 皆さんが自分が
アリだと思って下さい｡
アリ？
Please picture yourself as an ant.
An ant?
(野口さん)で ここに一本の線を
引きます｡地面に｡➡
I'm going to draw a line here.
まず 最初に線の上を
前後だけにしか歩けない➡
First,
picture yourself as a 1-D ant that can only walk on the line.
一次元アリさんだと
思って下さい｡皆さんは➡
You are an ant
線の上を前に行くか
後ろに行くしか出来ない｡➡
that can only move forward and backward.
そういうアリさんなんです｡
そこに僕が➡
Next, I place a stone on the line.
ぽっと 石を置いたとします｡
(六太ｱﾘ)何だ!?
そうすると 一次元アリさんは
前に行こうと思っても➡
At that point, the 1-D ant
won't be able to move forward
その一次元アリさんは
小石のせいで➡
because the stone is in the way.
前に行けなくなっちゃいますよね｡
つまり世界の終りなんですね｡➡
So that's the end of the ant's world.
そこに 前後と左右に行ける
二次元アリさんがやってきます｡
But then,
a 2-D ant comes along that can move forward, backward, left, and right.
H-Hey...
(一次元ｱﾘ)おい！
(一次元ｱﾘ)ダメだって！
線を出ちゃ｡
You're supposed to stay on the line.
誰が んなこと決めたんだ？
Who made up that rule?
The 2-D ant looks at the stone and says,
(野口さん)二次元アリさんは その
小石を見て言います｡➡
横に回って行けばいいじゃない｡
Good point.
"Why don't you go around?"
Don't worry...
大丈夫だって！ほらほら～｡
Come on!
そうして 二次元アリさんは
その小石を越えて➡
And so, the 2-D ant moves past the stone and continues onward.
また先に進むことが出来ました｡
(野口さん)そうして歩いて行くと
今度は横方向にも➡
After a while, they run into a stone wall, continuing endlessly in both directions.
ず～っと繋がっている
石の壁があったとします｡
(アリ達)アリ～!?
(野口さん)二次元アリさん➡
The ants are in trouble now.
また困っちゃいますね｡
前後に行っても左右に行っても➡
They can move forward, backward, left, or right, but they can't pass the wall.
その壁の向こう側には
行けなくなってしまう｡➡
Uh-oh, we can't get past this.
二次元アリさんにとっては
世界の終わりです｡➡
This is the end of the 2-D ant's world.
どうしていいか わからない｡
そこに今度は 前後と左右と➡
He doesn't know what to do.
And that's when
a 3-D ant comes along, capable of moving forward, backward, left, right, up, and down.
今度は上下にも行ける
三次元アリさんがやってきた｡➡
三次元アリさんは
その壁を見て言います｡➡
The 3-D ant looks at the wall and says,
乗り越えればいいじゃない｡
そして 三次元アリさんは➡
"Why don't you climb it?"
Stupid, it's dangerous!
And so, the 3-D ant
Come down!
横にず～っと繋がっている壁を
乗り越えて さらに新しい世界に➡
climbs over the wall to discover a new world.
進むことが出来ます｡
この話で僕が言いたいことは➡
The point I'm trying to make
上から見る あるいは下から見ると
いった 別の視点を持つ事で➡
is that when you see something from a new perspective, such as from above,
新しい解決策に
気がつくんじゃないかと｡➡
you may discover a new solution.
宇宙に人間が行くということは
単に遠くの星に行くだけでは➡
We aren't sending humans into space solely to travel to distant planets.
なくて 地上で僕達が今 抱えて
いる問題を新しい視点から見て➡
We're giving ourselves a new view of our problems on Earth,
and the opportunity to find a new solution.
解くことが出来るんじゃ
ないかなぁと｡それが 本当に➡
I believe that's the real reason we venture into space.
僕達が宇宙に行きたいっていう
理由じゃないかなぁと思います｡
なるほどね～｡
That makes sense...
＜野口さんのアリの話で➡
Noguchi's ant story was an instant hit with Hibito and me.
わたしと日々人は
すぐに納得したものだが＞
現在
But would it work on a hardheaded journalist?
がんこ
《この頑固そうなキャスターに
通用するんだろうか？》
《二次元アリの世界に ずっと
とどまっている この人に》
On someone who's spent her entire life in the 2-D ant world?
(手島)こういうのどう？
宇宙へ行く理由｡➡
How does this sound?
"The Reason for Space Exploration:
わたし達が宇宙で
仕事をすることは 新しい発見➡
Space exploration will lead
to new discoveries and technology.
新技術を生み出す
きっかけとなる｡人類にとって➡
This work is critical to society."
大事な仕事なんです｡みたいな｡
What do you think?
みぞぐち
(溝口)手島さん それ僕が言った
のと ほとんど同じですよ｡
Teshima,
that's basically what I just said.
びみょう
あ…そう？微妙に違うんだけどな｡
Oh, really?
It was a little different...
Teshima is a nervous wreck,
《落ち着きのない手島に➡
今 全く関係ない
ﾙｰﾋﾞｯｸｷｭｰﾌﾞをいじる富井…➡
while Tomii is playing with a Rubik's Cube instead of paying attention.
この２人が最後に
選ばれることはないな｡➡
Neither of them will be chosen at the end.
今ここに居ること自体が疑問だ｡
選ばれるのは真壁か 俺か 北村》
I have to wonder why they're even here.
It'll be Makabe, Kitamura, or me.
《真壁は仕切ろうとするのが
気に食わない｡➡
I don't like how Makabe is trying to be the leader.
ジャマなのは…真壁だ》
He is my
biggest obstacle.
(ケンジ)富井君はどう思う？
How about you, Tomii?
とみい
しゃべ
(富井)僕 喋ってもいいんですか？
Is it okay for me to talk?
当然だよ！最年少だからって
遠慮することはないよ｡
Of course!
You don't have to be shy just because you're the youngest here.
The American thinker Buckminster Fuller
しそうか
アメリカの思想家 ﾊﾞｯｸﾐﾝｽﾀｰ･ﾌﾗｰは
地球を｢宇宙船地球号｣という➡
once called our planet "Spaceship Earth".
乗り物だと言いました｡
一方 イギリスの科学者➡
On the other hand,
British scientist James Lovelock stated
ｼﾞｪｰﾑｽ･ﾗﾌﾞﾛｯｸは 地球を｢ガイア｣と
せいぶつ
いう生物だと言っています｡➡
that our planet was a life form named Gaia.
むじゅん
乗り物と生物…僕はこの矛盾が
気になっていました｡だけど➡
I was always puzzled
by the contrast between spaceship and life form.
But the British scientist Richard Dawkins helped tie it together.
イギリスの科学者 ﾘﾁｬｰﾄﾞ･ﾄﾞｰｷﾝｽの
言葉で繋がりました｡➡
人間もいわば
いでんし
地球という生命の遺伝子です｡➡
Humans can be considered the Earth's genes.
地球は自分のコピーを
つく
創ろうとします｡➡
The planet is trying to self-replicate.
ひつぜん
生き物として それは必然です｡➡
That is natural behavior for a life form.
ﾐﾋｬｴﾙ･ｴﾝﾃﾞは人間を
地球のガン細胞にたとえたけど➡
Michael Ende once compared humans to cancer cells,
僕の考えだと
せいしょく
人間は｢生殖細胞｣です｡ただ➡
but I believe that humans are germ cells.
However, there is the possibility that any of us
はかい
かたん
誰もが地球破壊に加担していて
ガン細胞になりうるという➡
could become the cancer cell that destroys Earth.
だけのことです｡宇宙へ行くのは
僕らが地球の遺伝子なら…➡
If we are truly Earth's genes, the purpose of space exploration
とつぜんへんい
突然変異が必要だからです｡
is because mutation is necessary.
《すごい｡喋るじゃん！》
Amazing!
He can really speak...
(北村)《こんな人だったの!?》
So he's one of those?
That's a fascinating opinion.
面白い意見だね｡
ただ…｢人間は地球の
遺伝子だからです｣って言っても➡
However,
I doubt this journalist will understand the explanation
このキャスターに
伝わりそうにないよ｡➡
that humans are the Earth's genes.
問題は彼女を納得させられる
抗議文を作ることだ｡➡
Our task is to write a letter that will win her over.
それこそが正解だよ｡
That would be the correct answer.
《正解か…
そんなものがあるのかな？➡
Correct answer...
Is there really a correct answer?
答は重要じゃない｡
きっとＪＡＸＡが見たいのは➡
The answer isn't what matters.
I'm sure JAXA is
僕らが話し合っている様子…➡
more interested in our discussion.
だけどなんだか この班は…》
But this team...
ん～…｢だから あんたみたい
なのが居なけりゃ➡
"If it weren't for people like you,
今頃みんな有休とって
火星に旅行してるハズだ｣｡
we would all be vacationing on Mars right now."
どうや これ？ズバッと｡
How was that?
I'm being blunt.
ズバッとしすぎじゃねえ？
A little too blunt.
大阪人気質ってやつか｡
Is this what they call the Osaka way?
言うとくけど 俺 京都やし｡
I'll have you know that I'm from Kyoto.
And, Nitta, yours wasn't any better!
それに新田
たいがい
お前の意見も大概やないか｡➡
外国に行って 自分の国の問題や
良さが改めて分かるように➡
Traveling to foreign countries offers perspective on your own country's good and bad qualities.
宇宙という広い世界に行って
初めて地球の良さが➡
Therefore, traveling to outer space will offer new perspective on our planet.
分かることもある｡
Is something wrong with that?
何か問題でも？
おもろない！ひねりがない！➡
Boring! Clichéd! Lame!
オチがない！ジブン 真面目か!?
Trying to be a goody two-shoes?
伊東さんの意見が一番分かり
やすかったような気がするね｡➡
I believe that Itou's letter makes the most sense.
宇宙空間での
医学分野の実験に関して➡
She provided concise explanation, with examples of the benefits
from conducting medical experiments in space.
かんけつ
実例も踏まえて簡潔に
説明されている｡
ありがとうございます｡
Thank you very much.
What about you, Nanba?
はぁ!?ジブン
線１本書いただけか!?➡
Huh?
You just drew a line after thirty minutes?
30分もかけて！
うっ！あ…いや これは➡
O-Oh, I just...
野口さんの｢三次元アリ｣の話を
思い出して書いただけで…｡
I drew a line because I was remembering Noguchi's 3-D ant story.
なんやそれ｡
What's that?
で 答はまとまったの？
お兄ちゃん｡
Then do you have an answer, big brother?
それでまあ 考えた結果➡
Well, after some thinking,
俺が出した答えは こっちで…｡
this is my answer.
[外:0DBCA01994FF3B306D62E6254E00A6DD]何やこれ 白紙やんけ！
What?
It's blank!
(職員)白紙!?
Blank?
Seriously?
(職員)ギブアップってことか？
He's giving up?
Hmm?
いやだから…
｢抗議はしない｣っていう答えだよ｡
My answer is that we don't protest.
Huh?
After considering the 3-D ant story,
三次元アリのことを考えてたら
なんかそう思えてきた｡
that makes the most sense.
ガチガチの二次元頭の人に
三次元の魅力や意味は➡
You can't use words to make a 2-D hardliner see the benefits of a 3-D world.
言葉じゃなかなか伝わらないよ｡
じゃあ どうすりゃ
いいかっつったら それは…｡
So what should you do?
Well...
連れて行くしかないよ
宇宙っていう三次元に｡
You must take her to the third dimension.
To outer space.
そのうち宇宙が近い時代が来て
誰も文句言わなくなるよ｡
Once space becomes more accessible, people will stop complaining.
Indeed.
確かに 飛行機だって
そうだったからね｡
That's what happened with airplanes.
No, that won't work!
いや アカンてそれじゃあ！
アカン アカン！
It won't work!
｢抗議文を書いて下さい｣ゆう
問いに｢抗議しない｣ちゅう答えは➡
They told us to write a letter of protest, so you can't come back and say that we won't protest!
きゃっか
ないわ！残念！却下!!
大体 この女がテレビで余計な➡
Too bad! Denied!
Besides, this woman is saying stuff on TV now.
発言したんは 今の話や｡
あくえいきょう
悪影響が出てんのは 今！➡
The negative effects are being felt now.
そんな先の時代まで
待ってられへん｡今すぐ抗議せな！
We don't have time to wait.
We have to protest now!
心配ないよ｡日々人がいる｡
Don't worry.
We have Hibito.
What?
もうすぐ 日々人が月に立つんだ｡
日本人が初めて月に行くんだよ｡
It won't be long before Hibito stands on the moon.
He'll be the first Japanese person on the moon.
みんなきっとワクワクしながら
夜空を見上げると思うな｡
Everyone will be excited, as they look up at the night sky...
That will make space more accessible
そしたら みんなの意識の中に
宇宙が降りて来て➡
もっと宇宙が近くなる｡
to everyone's minds.
誰に批判されたって
日々人が帳消しにしてくれるよ｡
Hibito will cancel out all the negative publicity.
(ガチャ キィー…)
(職員)全班 解答が出ました｡
The teams have submitted their responses.
(職員)どれも なかなか
いい抗議文ですね｡
They're all very well written.
(職員)Ａ班は結局 伊東さんの
文章を提出ですか｡
So team A
decided to use Itou's letter?
(職員)確かに 南波君のは答えに
なってなかったから➡
Since Nanba's response wasn't really an answer,
that was a smart decision.
だとう
妥当な決断ですよ｡
茄子田理事長
これだけ説得力のある文章なら➡
Director Nasuda,
since we have this excellent letter of protest,
本当に出しても
いいんじゃないですか？
should we go ahead and submit it?
う～ん 僕も
そう思ってんだけどね…やめた｡
Hmm...
That was the plan,
but not now.
Huh?
(茄子田)わたくし達には
そんなヒマないよ｡
We're out of time.
The stars I admired were too bright for me
so I quietly closed my eyes
I have faith in you, as you stand alone, full of doubts
I'm right here, next to you
Come now, take my hand and hold it tight
If you do, we will always
have hope, shine with light
and overcome whatever we might face
Do you see how wonderful this world is
and how our future unfolds?
Even the tears we shed and could not put into words
will one day dry up, I am sure
One by one the smiles spread
and ascend towards the starlit sky
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#14 Broken Glasses
and the Sole of the Foot
＜閉鎖環境での試験が続く中
私達Ａ班で 大事件が起こる＞
As life goes on in the sealed environment,
something big happens in team A!
＜福田さんの変顔が
すごすぎます＞
Fukuda
can make some really funny faces!
＜ある意味 それも事件｡
だけど ホントの事件は➡
That was also big.
But I'm talking about Fukuda's glasses!
福田さんのメガネ！
福田さんのメガネが メガネが…＞
His glasses were... His glasses were...
Stop babbling about the glasses!
＜メガネ メガネ うるさいわ！
わざと踏み潰したんちゃうで＞
I didn't step on them deliberately!
＜そう！やっさんが
福田さんのメガネを踏み潰し➡
Yes!
Ya stepped on Fukuda's glasses.
大変なことに…＞
(古谷)＜だから わざとちゃう＞
It's terrible!
It wasn't on purpose!
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Broken Glasses and the Sole of the Foot"
My dream hasn't aged a day!
＜私の夢は 年を取っていない＞
パンパカパ～ン！
今週の宇宙写真です！
This Week's Space Photo
This week's space photo!
スッゲ～！
Awesome!